<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-event library="SearchBuilder">
	<name>dtsb-inserted</name>
	<summary>An element from the init function has been inserted into the dom</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<type type="event">
		<description>Triggered when a HTML element created in the `-init searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].init` function is inserted into the document.</description>
	</type>

	<description>
This event is triggered whenever one of the elements created in the `-init searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].init` is inserted by SearchBuilder into the document. This is useful as for some jQuery elements such as Select2, the HTML element needs to be in the dom before initialisation so that the functionality is correct.

This event is triggered at the following points

* Whenever the condition `-tag select` element is changed
* Whenever the data `-tag select` element is changed
* Whenever the criteria is created 
* Whenever a criteria is added to the group
* Whenever a criteria in removed from the group
* Whenever a criteria is indented or outdented

Admittedly, this is a large number of places for this to occur, however it is necessary.

When the data or the condition `-tag select` element has their value changed the value elements need to be reset. The easiest way to do this is to remove the value elements and initialise them to their default state again.

When adding or removing criteria in the same group it is possible that more buttons need to be added or removed from the criteria that remain, again the easiest way to do this is to remove and rebuild the entire criteria, applying the values that previously existed.

For indenting and outdenting the criteria are removed from one group and added to another, so their dom elements need to be removed from the original and added to the next.
        
The event is triggered on the original element(s) created in the init function to be used to retrieve the value from the user. This means that the best place to set listeners for this event is also in the init function by listening for `-event dtsb-inserted`.
	</description>

	<example title="Initialise Select2 on a Select Element Once Inserted"><![CDATA[
{
	init: function (that, fn, preDefined = null) {
		let el = $('<select>');
		$(el).prepend('<option></option>');

		// ...

		$(el).on('dtsb-inserted', function () {
			if ($(el).hasClass('select2-hidden-accessible')) {
				$(el).select2('destroy');
			}

			$(el).select2({ placeholder: 'Value' });

			if (preDefined !== null) {
				$(el).val(preDefined[0]);
				$(el).trigger('input');
			}
		});

		// ...
	}
}

]]></example>
</dt-event>