<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<dt-option library="SearchBuilder">
	<name>searchBuilder.conditions[type]</name>
	<summary>The object structure for the type object containing additional conditions for SearchBuilder</summary>
	<since>1.0.0</since>

	<type type="object">
		<description>
            An object populated with key-value pairs of objects (`-init searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond]`) that contain the information necessary to add a new condition.
        </description>
	</type>

	<default value="object">

	</default>
	<description>
		<![CDATA[
This is useful as it allows custom conditions to be added to SearchBuilder should the standard ones not be enough. It also allows for the standard conditions to be removed or edited to fit your own needs. Here the `type` in `-init searchBuilder.conditions[type]` is the type for the column, for more details refer to `-init columns.type`.

Each key-value pair on the `-init searchBuilder.conditions[type]` object is used to represent a single condition. The structure of the value for these is documented at `-init searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond]`.

The standard conditions can be removed, edited or added to. The manual page for [custom conditions](../extensions/searchbuilder/customConditions.html) covers this in detail.

Note: When using a custom decimal place character, the SearchBuilder internals will replace this with a `.` so that the correct processing can take place. It is worth bearing this in mind when customising the functions that each condition runs.

## Examples

There are two examples that create custom conditions using initialisation options. They both show how to add a custom condition to the `num` column type, but the process is the same for other column types.

* [Custom Multiple Of](../extensions/SearchBuilder/examples/customisation/customMultiple.html)
* [+- 5](../extensions/SearchBuilder/examples/customisation/customConditions.html)

There is also an example that shows how to use a plug-in to add a custom condition.

* [Plug-in Example](../extensions/SearchBuilder/examples/customisation/plugin.html)

		]]>
	</description>

<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond]</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].isInputValid</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].search</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].conditionName</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].inputValue</related>
<related type="init">searchBuilder.conditions[type][cond].init</related>
<related type="init">columns.type</related>

</dt-option>
